<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xml:lang="en" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc/>
        <profileDesc>
            <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="Sassawwaw"><persName><forename>Sassawwaw</forename></persName></person>
            </particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text xml:lang="en">
        <body>
            <p>This deed or writing bearing date this present
                <date calendar="julian" datingMethod="julian" when-custom="1660-06-29">twenty‐ninth day of June,
                    one thousand six hundred and sixty</date>,
                witnesseth, that I, <persName ref="#Sassawwaw">Socho</persName>
                an Indian Captain of Narraganset, being the true nnd lawful owner of a tract of land
                called Misquamicoke, for a valuable consideration in hand paid to my content, have bargained and sold unto
                William Vaughan, Robert Stanton, John Fairfield, Hugh Moshur, James Longbottom, all of Nuport in Rhode‐Island
                and others their associates, which said tract of land being bounded as followeth, Easterly by a place called
                Weecapaug or Passpatanage joining to the Nianticut land, on the South by the main sea, on the West by Pawcutuck
                river, and so up the chief river or stream northerly and northeasterly to a place called Quequatuck or
                Quequachanocke, and from thence on a straight line to the first named bounds called Wecapoag or Pachatanage
                joining upon the Nianticut land as abovesaid; which said tract of land so butted and bounded as aforesaid, I the
                said <persName ref="#Sassawwaw">Socho</persName>
                do for myself, my heirs, executors, administrators, and assigns, surrender up all right, title, claim
                or interest whatsoever to the said land or any privilege appertaining to the said land, fully instating the said
                William Vaughan, Robert Stanton, John Fairfield, Hugh Mosier, James Longbottom and their associates, their
                heirs, executors, administrators or assigns, to the said land and proprieties thereof, to ihe worlds end. In
                witness whereof I the said <persName ref="#Sassawwaw">Sosoa</persName>
                have set to my hand and seal the year and date abovesaid.</p>
            <p>The mark of <persName ref="#Sassawwaw">SOSOA</persName>.</p>
            <p>L. S.</p>
            <list>
                <head>Sealed signed in presence of</head>
                <item>JEREMY CLARKE,</item>
                <item>LATHAM CLARKE,</item>
                <item>HENRY CLARK,</item>
                <item>AWASHWASH his mark.</item>
                <item>The mark W of NUCUM, Interpreter.</item>
                <item>GEORGE WEBB,</item>
                <item>GEORGE GARDINER.</item>
            </list>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
